[Music] [excited] I asked a private PDF one question —
it returned an accurate answer in 0.8 seconds.
In this video I'm showing how to build a RAG agent from scratch
and how to reproduce this result.
[brief pause] We'll cover architecture, tools, and a sample use case
so you can copy the repo and run it locally.
First — why RAG? [calm] It's often faster and cheaper
than full fine-tuning for document Q&A.
00:15 — Quick context: the core deliverables are code, configs, and metrics.
You'll get latency and accuracy numbers for each step.
00:30 — Preview demo: watch me query a private PDF.
I'll show the vector retrieval and the final generated answer.
[Sound Effect] Live demo running — retriever returns top 3 hits,
then the generator composes the final response.
00:45 — Architecture overview: embeddings into a vector DB,
then a retriever and an LLM generator.
We'll compare Pinecone and FAISS, and show when to pick each one.
[emphasis] I'll explain tradeoffs: latency, cost, and scale.
01:00 — Tools & stack: LangChain and LlamaIndex examples,
OpenAI or other embeddings, and vector DB options.
01:15 — Sample dataset notes: chunking strategy, metadata, and filtering.
Small changes here hugely affect retrieval accuracy.
[excited] 01:30 — Demo: inspect the retrieval hits—see which chunks matched,
and how the prompt template guides the generator.
01:45 — Early optimization tips: batch embeddings,
cache frequent queries, and use sparse filters to reduce noise.
02:00 — What's next: we'll deep dive into deployment,
scaling to 1,000 users and monitoring p95 latency.
[calm] Now let's build: start with embeddings—I'll show code for batching
and a simple Python example using OpenAI embeddings.
[Sound Effect] Create your index: example shows Pinecone init,
FAISS local index creation, and metadata mapping.
[excited] Retriever tuning: adjust k, score threshold, and hybrid search
for better precision and less hallucination.
Prompt engineering: include the source chunks, system instruction,
and an explicit "cite sources" constraint to reduce fabrication.
Deployment notes: containerize with Docker, add a Gunicorn/Uvicorn server,
and set up simple concurrency limits.
Security: encrypt vectors at rest if necessary, apply access controls,
and remove PII before indexing when required.
Evaluation: run retrieval QA tests, measure exact match and MRR,
and check hallucination rates on an eval dataset.
[encouraging] Repo link is pinned in the top comment — run the demo,
then come back with questions about your dataset.
[Music] Subscribe for weekly production AI builds — next video:
scaling RAG to 1,000 concurrent users. [excited]