[excited] RAG agent tutorial 2025 — I'll build a working RAG that answers any PDF.
Preview: final answer shown now so you know the payoff. Watch for the one config that breaks relevance.
Quick context: RAG = retrieval + LLM. It saves tokens and gives grounded answers by fetching relevant passages before the model generates.
[Sound Effect] Let's ingest the docs — chunking rule: 500–1,000 tokens with overlap 50–100 tokens for context.
Command: run embedding batch jobs (use async batching). This reduces API calls and improves throughput. I'll show exact snippet now.
Indexing: FAISS for local low-latency; Pinecone for managed scale. Tune dimension and metric (cosine vs dot). Now we run a test retrieval.
[emphasis] Retriever tuning: increase k, re-rank top results with cross-encoder or use simple semantic similarity + lexical signals.
Deployment notes: containerize the retriever service, autoscale the embedding workers, and instrument relevance/latency metrics.
Final test: deployed agent answers a fresh query with high relevance. [excited] That's the payoff — reproducible and deployable.
[Music] Recap & next steps: repo in pinned comment, like if this saved you tokens, and subscribe for the low-latency RAG deep dive.